joystickdivision.com 2016-12-29

# Privacy Policy | New York News, Food, Culture and Events | Village Voice

### Village Voice, LLC

This Privacy Policy is effective as of October 4, 2016.

This Privacy Policy describes the practices that Village Voice, LLC ("Village Voice") follows with respect to the collection, maintenance and use of information submitted on villagevoice.com (the "Site"). This Privacy Policy applies only to information we collect from this Site, and does not apply to any other website or business activity of Village Voice. By using our Site, and/or providing information to us, you consent to the collection, maintenance and use of this information by us.

If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site and exit immediately. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to these terms means that you accept those changes. We will give you notice of the revised Privacy Policy by posting the revised policy on the Site and by revising the "effective date" set forth above.

### Information We Collect

We collect and maintain personally identifiable information and automatic information.

### Personally Identifiable Information

"Personally identifiable information" is information that tells us who you are, such as your name, screen name, email address, postal address, phone number, credit card information, birth date/year and gender.

Village Voice collects and maintains personally identifiable information about you only when you provide it to us. For example, we may collect and maintain personally identifiable information about you when you register for or participate in contests, sweepstakes, promotions, polls, surveys, newsletters and text messages (including contests, sweepstakes, promotions, polls, surveys, newsletters and text messages of certain third parties). We may also collect and maintain personally identifiable information when you post an ad, submit comments to the Site or letters to the editor, submit events for inclusion on our Site, purchase event tickets from us, or otherwise provide it to us when you contact us.

If you do not provide information to us, you may be unable to use certain features of the Site. For example, you cannot post comments in connection with certain articles or register for the Site, contests, surveys or newsletters unless you provide certain information. Also, you will not be able to submit events for inclusion on our Site or purchase event tickets if you do not provide certain information.

### Automatic Information and Cookies

"Automatic information" is information automatically collected whenever you visit our site. For example, automatic information includes information collected by our web server (which may be hosted by a third party) that your web browser makes available whenever you visit our Site, such as your browser type and capabilities, network properties, the site that you visited before viewing our Site, content viewed on the Site, and your geographic location. We currently use, or may use, such information in various ways:

Aggregated data: We maintain automatic information in aggregated form, not associated with your IP address or personally identifiable information. 

IP address tracking: All computers and servers on the Internet use IP addresses to recognize and communicate with each other. We collect and maintain IP addresses to administer and analyze our Site and report aggregate information (such as how many visitors we have and how many visitors see and click on particular advertisements).

We may associate your IP address with your personally identifiable information and may maintain, use and disclose such information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy below.

### How do you use tagging, cookies, and other identifiers to collect information?

Cookies: This Site uses "cookies." A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a web site and stored on your computer's hard drive. Village Voice serves cookies to track individual site usage for later aggregation and for other purposes explained in this policy. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but you may not be able to take full advantage of our Site's features if you do. 

**ComScore**  
As part of our market research effort, we deploy comScore web tags throughout the Site. The comScore tagging is not used to identify the user visiting a page. As an example, the tags may collect such data as a timestamp, the URL, and the title of the web page. These tags send a message to comScore that causes a comScore cookie to be dropped or a mobile identifier to be accessed. This process, which we refer to below as “browser-level measuring,” is done so that comScore is able to identify browser-level behavior such as new versus repeat visitors to a website or page. ComScore uses the combination of tagging, cookies, and mobile identifiers (where relevant) to help Village Voice count users who have visited and seen a page or various parts of a page. In certain instances where comScore is being used to measure an advertisement, the cookie may be set by an advertising network or advertiser. If this advertising network or advertiser is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance, you may opt out of such tracking by clicking [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).  Please note that you can view and delete these cookies using the features of your browser or by installing a third party tool to view the cookies.

ComScore may use a third party service provider to obtain non-personally identifiable information and add that data to our measurements. Either comScore or the third party service provider may initiate the process which results in this association, and this process may involve comScore triggering the dropping of a cookie belonging to the third party service provider. We may also associate the anonymous unique identifier within the comScore cookie on your computer or device with information obtained from other sources (such as consumer preference reporting companies) using confidential matching procedures.

**Google Analytics**  
We use Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to help analyze how users use the Site. Google Analytics uses Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve our Site and Services. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit the Site, rather than your name or other personally identifying information. We do not combine the information generated through the use of Google Analytics with your Personal Data. Although Google Analytics plants a persistent Cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit the Site, the Cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy.

We do not and cannot use cookies or IP address tracking to retrieve personally identifiable information from your computer.

### How long do you retain the information you collect?

The data collected through browser-level measurement is typically maintained for up to 90 days. Such data may be aggregated and used for analytical purposes indefinitely. Additionally, in certain circumstances, selected anonymous records relating to the Site may be maintained indefinitely.

### How can I opt out?

**comScore**  
You can control your level of participation in comScore’s market research programs, along with other research programs that are operated by comScore, Inc. or its affiliates.

To opt-out of having comScore’s market research programs associated with your browser, please [click here](http://www.scorecardresearch.com/optout.aspx?newlanguage=1). If you choose to opt-out, a cookie will be placed on your computer instructing us to disable our ability to browser-level track your website visitation while on a website with a comScore web tag installed. However, if your browser does not accept cookies, or if you delete all of your cookies, then this browser-level tracking may occur. Additionally, this opt-out is only effective when you are using the Internet browser you were using when you opted-out.

**Google Analytics**  
You can opt-out of the Google Analytics Advertising Features we use through Google Ads Settings, Ads Settings for mobile apps, or any other available means, including The Network Advertising Initiative’s consumer opt-out at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). You may also use Google Analytics' currently available opt-outs for the web. 

**Online Behavioral Advertising**  
Village Voice may tailor advertisements on the Site to a user's apparent interests, based on user browsing activity. That is, ads may be displayed for you on the Site based on the pages and content that you view. This is sometimes known as first-party online behavioral advertising. Also, your viewing activity on the Site may be shared with advertising networks, so that they can display ads for you, which they believe will interest you, on other sites, not affiliated with Village Voice. This is sometimes known as third-party online behavioral advertising. Village Voice attempts to deal with advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, but at times ad networks that are not NAI or DAA participants may have access to your activity on the Site, and hence may use that information in connection with displaying ads to you on other sites. 

Advertising networks that are members of Network Advertising Initiative or that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance have subscribed to certain principles relating to collection and use of information, and may permit users to direct whether or how information about their viewing activities are used for advertising purposes. To register your preferences or choices, or to opt out of behavioral advertising offered by participants in these programs, visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

If you change browsers or computers, or delete the cookies on your computer, you may need to re-enter your preferences or opt-out.

Web Beacons: The Site uses web beacons, which provide website operators and third parties a means to deliver a graphic image on a web page or in an email message for the purpose of gathering data. The Site uses web beacons to gather automatic information such as the duration of a visit to the Site, the web pages viewed, a user's geographical information (e.g., city, state, zip code), IP address, and type of web browser.

### Use and Disclosure of Information

We maintain and use personally identifiable information for the purpose or purposes for which it is provided and for purposes specified in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may maintain and use personally identifiable information to send newsletters and text messages that you have opted to receive; to establish your online account and recognize you when you return to the Site; to contact you regarding contests, promotions, polls, and surveys; to complete the sale of event tickets; to provide customer support; or to otherwise communicate with you regarding our Site, an ad you posted, an event you submitted to the Site, or your comments or letters to the editor.

We may also maintain and use your personally identifiable information to attribute your comments, letters to the editor and/or other submissions to the Site to you. As has traditionally been the case with our print editions, we may require that you supply certain information to us (such as your real name, daytime telephone number and/or e-mail address) in connection with comments and other submissions to the Site. That is because we may need to contact you, and because your identity may be important to understand your point of view. If you send us comments or other submissions, we reserve the right to publish them in print or display them on this Site in full or in edited form. We normally honor requests to withhold your name and address when provided in connection with comments and other submissions, both in print and on-line, but we reserve the right to use, discuss and report facts that we consider newsworthy relating to submissions even if it might reveal or tend to reveal the poster's identity.

We may combine personally identifiable information and automatic information we obtain from you or your activities with other data concerning or relating to the behavioral and demographic attributes of our customers, in order to identify our best customers, reach them effectively, understand their interests and best manage our relationships with them.

We may also use personally identifiable information to send you advertisements, promotions and information about the Site, Village Voice and our partners. 

We may disclose personally identifiable information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may have breached our Terms of Use or who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property, other users of our Site, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. We may also disclose personally identifiable information when we reasonably believe that the law requires it.

If you choose to provide your personally identifiable information for the purposes of a third-party contest, promotion, poll, survey or newsletter, your personally identifiable information will be given to Village Voice and to the third-party advertiser/sponsor involved with the relevant contest, promotion, poll, survey or newsletter and/or its agents and affiliates. For rules or requirements for contests, promotions, polls, surveys and/or newsletters, please see the applicable page on our Site.

We occasionally have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and joint ventures that perform functions on our behalf, such as credit card processing, shipping or stocking orders, providing customer service, data combination, etc. They are provided access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions.

In the event of a sale of Village Voice or a sale of substantially all Village Voice assets, personally identifiable information may be one of the business assets transferred or sold.

We may maintain and use automatic information to track how our visitors use the Site, study traffic patterns, and run and maintain the site, and we and other third parties may provide targeted advertisements to you based on such data.

We may share aggregated data with our advertisers and other marketing and business partners.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. 

### Unsubscribing

You may terminate any ongoing communications you receive from Village Voice via e-mail (such as newsletters, subscriptions, contest results, survey inquiries, etc.) by (1) clicking the "unsubscribe" link that is available within the communication received, or (2) through your online profile.

### Children

Some of the material on this Site is for mature audiences, and parents and guardians should take responsibility for monitoring their children's use of the Site. Children under the age of 13 should not use this Site. We do not intentionally collect personally identifiable information from users of the Site who are under the age of thirteen. 

### Links to Other Sites

This Site provides links to websites maintained by other organizations. Village Voice provides these links as a convenience to users, but it does not operate, control or endorse such sites. Village Voice also disclaims any responsibility for the information on those sites and any products or services offered on such sites. Please review the privacy policies of these sites. Village Voice is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties, and does not make any warranties or representations that any linked sites (or even this Site) will function without error or interruption, that defects will be corrected, or that the sites and their servers are free of viruses and other problems that can harm your computer. Village Voice disclaims any responsibility for transactions conducted on those sites and cannot vouch for the security of the information submitted in those transactions.

### E-Commerce and Our Secure Server

We use reasonable efforts to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized use or disclosure. Unfortunately, information transmitted on the Internet and/or stored on systems attached to the Internet are not 100% secure. As a result, we do not ensure, warrant or guarantee the security or integrity of such information. We will not be responsible for disclosure of any information due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties.

### Updates and Changes to Your Information.

If your personally identifiable information changes, you may correct and/or update it by sending us an email. You may also view, correct and/or update your personally identifiable information by accessing your profile on the Site. 

### More Questions? 

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please e-mail them to [privacyadministrator@villagevoice.com](mailto:privacyadministrator@villagevoice.com), and be sure to indicate the specific site you are visiting and the nature of your question or concern.
